<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Terminal | Tutorial for Maddie]]></title>
  <link href="http://Dillon-Benson.github.io/blog/categories/terminal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Dillon-Benson.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-15T15:35:52-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://Dillon-Benson.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dillon Benson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use the Terminal (Part 3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://Dillon-Benson.github.io/blog/2013/08/01/how-to-use-the-terminal-part-3/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-01T14:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://Dillon-Benson.github.io/blog/2013/08/01/how-to-use-the-terminal-part-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome! After reading the <a href="/blog/2013/07/18/how-to-use-the-terminal/">first</a> and <a href="/blog/2013/07/20/how-to-use-the-terminal-part-2/">second</a> tutorials you should already know what a command is, its arguments, and options. You&rsquo;ve learned several commands so far. This post will be your final tutorial on how to use the terminal. In this post you&rsquo;ll learn a few more essential commands.</p>

<h2>Renaming files and directories</h2>

<p>Renaming files and directories is easy. The syntax of renaming a directory is the same as that of renaming of file and looks like this:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>mv foo bar
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
As you can see the name of the command we&rsquo;re using here is &ldquo;mv&rdquo; and it has 2 arguments, the file (or directory) to be renamed and the new name for that file (or directory) respectively.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what is happening:
Say we have a file with the name &ldquo;foo&rdquo;&hellip;<br/>
<img src="/images/foo-for-mv.png"><br/>
Now we want to rename that &ldquo;foo&rdquo; file to &ldquo;bar"<br/>
So we issue an "mv&rdquo; command with &ldquo;foo&rdquo; as the first argument and &ldquo;bar&rdquo; as the second argument. Again Like this:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>mv foo bar
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
After executing this command, you can see that the &ldquo;foo&rdquo; file has been renamed to &ldquo;bar&rdquo; by using &ldquo;ls&rdquo; to see all the files in the current directory:<br/>
<img src="/images/bar-for-mv.png"><br/>
Keep in mind that this works for renaming directories as well. This syntax is the same for files and directories.
That&rsquo;s all there is to renaming things!</p>

<h2>Copying files</h2>

<p>Copying files has the same syntax as renaming files. The one exception is that the second argument is the name of the file you want to copy the first argument to.
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>cp foo bar
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
This is saying copy the the file named &ldquo;foo&rdquo; to a newly created file named &ldquo;bar&rdquo;. Note that the first and second arguments should not be the same. This is because 2 or more files in the same directory CANNOT have the same name.<br/>
Before issuing the &ldquo;cp&rdquo; command you would see something like this:
<img src="/images/foo-for-mv.png">
See the file named &ldquo;foo&rdquo;?
After executing the &ldquo;cp&rdquo; command you should see something like this:
<img src="/images/bar-for-cp.png">
Notice how &ldquo;foo&rdquo; and &ldquo;bar&rdquo; are there. This is because you copied &ldquo;foo&rdquo; into &ldquo;bar&rdquo;. Essentially this means you have 2 copies of &ldquo;foo&rdquo; but with the other file named as &ldquo;bar&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>Copying directories</h2>

<p>Remember the &ldquo;rm&rdquo; command for directories? You would have to say:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>rm -rf somedirectory
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
Remembering the &ldquo;-rf&rdquo; option to &ldquo;rm&rdquo;, this should have removed the directory. However not remembering it, the terminal would complain that &ldquo;somedirectory&rdquo; is a directory and that you cannot remove a directory without the &ldquo;-rf&rdquo; option. The same goes for copying directories!
Assuming you have a directory named &ldquo;somedirectory&rdquo;, The syntax of copying a directory will look like this:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>cp -rf somedirectory anotherdirectory
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
Where &ldquo;somedirectory&rdquo; is the directory you want to copy and &ldquo;anotherdirectory&rdquo; is the name of the newly created directory that you want &ldquo;somedirectory&rdquo; to be copied into.
And that&rsquo;s all there is to that.</p>

<p>Be sure that the last 3 posts make complete sense to you. If they don&rsquo;t please leave a comment or read them over again. In the next post I&rsquo;m going to prepare you for programming in Ruby by setting up some &ldquo;pre-ruby&rdquo; stuff. See you in a few!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how to use the Terminal (part 2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://Dillon-Benson.github.io/blog/2013/07/20/how-to-use-the-terminal-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-20T13:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://Dillon-Benson.github.io/blog/2013/07/20/how-to-use-the-terminal-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back Maddie! If you haven&rsquo;t read the <a href="http://dillon-benson.github.io/blog/2013/07/18/how-to-use-the-terminal/">first part</a> of this tutorial, I strongly suggest that you do. If you have already read it, then you should be ready for this tutorial. In this post I will cover creation and deletion of files, how to delete directories the right way, and quickly find out what&rsquo;s inside of a file. All this will be done with the power of the terminal. Remember, I strongly advise you to read the <a href="http://dillon-benson.github.io/blog/2013/07/18/how-to-use-the-terminal/">first section</a> before this.</p>

<h2>Creating and deleting files</h2>

<p>Creating and deleting files is an important part in becoming good with the terminal. Let&rsquo;s first start with creating files. Creating files is similar to creating a directory with the &ldquo;mkdir&rdquo; command from the previous section. However instead of using &ldquo;mkdir&rdquo; we use the &ldquo;touch&rdquo; command. The main purpose of &ldquo;touch&rdquo; is to generate a file with whatever name you want. To specify the name of the file you just pass the &ldquo;touch&rdquo; command an argument:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>touch foo
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
where &ldquo;foo&rdquo; would be the name of the newly created file.<br/>
or
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>touch bar
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
where &ldquo;bar&rdquo; would be the name of the newly created file.<br/>
As you can see the name of the command was &ldquo;touch&rdquo; and it has 1 argument specifying the name of the file. In these cases the name of file would be &ldquo;foo&rdquo; or &ldquo;bar&rdquo;.<br/>
Deleting files is pretty straight foward. You do this with the &ldquo;rm&rdquo; command. &ldquo;rm&rdquo; is short for remove. Just like the &ldquo;touch&rdquo; command, &ldquo;rm&rdquo; takes 1 argument specifying the name of the file that you wish to delete. Let&rsquo;s say you have a file named &ldquo;foo&rdquo;. When you use the &ldquo;ls&rdquo; command you should see something like this:<br/>
<img src="/images/ls-foo.png"><br/>
See the file named &ldquo;foo&rdquo;. Now you want to delete it. To do that you would just use:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>rm foo
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
&ldquo;foo&rdquo; is the only argument to the &ldquo;rm&rdquo; command this time.<br/>
Now when you use the &ldquo;ls&rdquo; command you see it has been deleted and disappeared from the directory.
<img src="/images/ls-foo-deleted.png">
Like this.<br/>
Now that you got the hang of creating and deleting files, it&rsquo;s time to show you how to delete directories.</p>

<h2>Deleting directories</h2>

<p>Removing a directory is just like removing a file. In fact it&rsquo;s the same command, &ldquo;rm&rdquo;. However, it&rsquo;s time to introduce a new concept to commandss. You know that commands have 0 or more arguments.
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nb">cd </span>foo
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
This has a command, &ldquo;cd&rdquo;, and an argument, &ldquo;foo&rdquo;. Turns out that commands have another nice features called options and they&rsquo;re a special form of arguments. Options are arguments that are prefixed with &ldquo;&ndash;&rdquo; or &ldquo;&mdash;&rdquo;. The main purpose of options are to specify how you want a command to be run. Keep in mind however that not all commands have options. It turns out that the &ldquo;rm&rdquo; command has a special option for deleting directories. &ldquo;-rf&rdquo;. This means remove a directory with recursive force. Don&rsquo;t worry about what that means for now. Just know that &ldquo;-rf&rdquo; along side of &ldquo;rm&rdquo; is used for deleting directories. Let&rsquo;s say our home directory looks something like this:
<img src="/images/foo-directory.png">
Notice the &ldquo;foo&rdquo; directory? If we want to delete this, all we need to do is issue an &ldquo;rm&rdquo; command like this:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>rm -rf foo
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
Where &ldquo;rm&rdquo; is the remove command, &ldquo;-rf&rdquo; the recursive force option we&rsquo;re using, and &ldquo;foo&rdquo; being the argument specifying the directory we want to remove.</p>

<h2>showing what&rsquo;s in a file</h2>

<p>There a nice command called &ldquo;cat&rdquo; that&rsquo;s used for showing what&rsquo;s inside of a file. Let&rsquo;s say that sometime in the future when you begin programming your first ruby code you have a file named &ldquo;hello.rb&rdquo; (The &ldquo;.rb&rdquo; in the file name means it&rsquo;s a ruby file). Now if you want to see what&rsquo;s inside of this just use &ldquo;cat&rdquo; with an argument. As you might have already guessed, yes, &ldquo;cat&rdquo; takes one argument specifying the name of the file you want to see the content of. So issuing:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>cat hello.rb
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div><br/>
May result in something that looks like this:<br/>
<img src="/images/cat-hello-rb.png">
Below the &ldquo;cat&rdquo; command you see ruby code. This is what&rsquo;s inside of the &ldquo;hello.rb&rdquo; file. Ruby code!</p>

<p>I hope this tutorial went good for you. If you have any questions please leave a comment. Make sure you have a good grip on what you&rsquo;ve learned so far. We&rsquo;re not done with the terminal tutorials yet. It&rsquo;s crucial you understand how to use it before you begin programming. Thanks for reading. See you soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how to use the terminal]]></title>
    <link href="http://Dillon-Benson.github.io/blog/2013/07/18/how-to-use-the-terminal/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-18T20:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://Dillon-Benson.github.io/blog/2013/07/18/how-to-use-the-terminal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey Maddie! Welcome to your first tutorial. Today you&rsquo;ll learn what a terminal is and how to use it. Simply, a terminal is where you enter commands that directly deal with a computer. It can be used to tell which files are in a folder, move files, rename files and folders, browse files and see what&rsquo;s in them, and so much more. By the way when you&rsquo;re using a terminal you call <strong>&ldquo;folders&rdquo;, &ldquo;directories&rdquo;</strong>. Programmers prefer terminals over your everyday windows because they&rsquo;re faster and more flexible with the ways you interact with a computer. Also without terminals there would be a significant decrease in performance of programs running on your computer. There are several different types of terminals. The most important difference between them is the operating system that uses it. For example Windows has their own special kind of terminal called DOS. While most other major operating system such as Mac OSX and Linux uses a UNIX based terminal that many people refer to as a Shell. Our primary focus will be on the UNIX Shell or for our purpose we&rsquo;ll just call it terminal.</p>

<p>Before we can start using the terminal you have to know how to open it. I like to do it the fast way by holding Command and pressing space. When you do this you&rsquo;ll see a blue and white search bar appear at the top right of your screen that says &ldquo;Spotlight&rdquo;. When you see this, type ITerm and press enter. If that doesn&rsquo;t work you can just click on &ldquo;Finder&rdquo; and go to <strong>Applications > ITerm.</strong><br/>
Either way you do it, you should see a window that pops up that looks something like this:<br/>
<img src="/images/iterm-open.png"><br/>
Right now you&rsquo;re in your &ldquo;home&rdquo; folder or as we call it your &ldquo;home&rdquo; directory. Test it out by typing:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nb">echo </span>hello
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div><br/>
and press enter.<br/>
If you did this correctly you should see &ldquo;hello&rdquo; was outputted below the line you just typed. You just entered your first command! A command consists of a name (in this case &ldquo;echo&rdquo;) and 0 or more arguments (in this case &ldquo;hello&rdquo; being the only argument). As you can tell all the &ldquo;echo&rdquo; command does is, well, echo whatever it&rsquo;s arguments are. Always remember that a command won&rsquo;t execute or run until your press enter on your keyboard. Since this is your first day we&rsquo;re just going to mess around with the most frequently used commands. The ones I&rsquo;ll be teaching today are &lsquo;ls&rsquo;, &lsquo;cd&rsquo;, and &lsquo;mkdir&rsquo;. Let&rsquo;s start with ls by simply typing:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>ls
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
You should see a bunch of things that were output such as &ldquo;Downloads&rdquo;, &ldquo;Movies&rdquo;, &ldquo;Music&rdquo;, &ldquo;Documents&rdquo;, and most likely some other stuff. the &ldquo;ls&rdquo; command in this case taking 0 arguments simply shows all of the files and folders in a directory. It&rsquo;s purpose is to show what files and folders exist in a directory. That&rsquo;s kind of useful! And now let&rsquo;s use &ldquo;cd&rdquo;. No, it has nothing to do with CD&rsquo;s that contain music lol. &ldquo;cd&rdquo; is short for change directory. let&rsquo;s &ldquo;change directory&rdquo; to &ldquo;Downloads&rdquo; by typing:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nb">cd </span>Downloads
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
At this point you should be in the Downloads directory. This is where all the files you have downloaded are stored and remember you can see all these files by typing:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>ls
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
So the &ldquo;cd&rdquo; command takes 1 argument. This argument should be the directory that you want to go in to and in our case that 1 argument was &ldquo;Downloads&rdquo;.
To go back to the home directory simply type:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>cd ../</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
The &ldquo;../&rdquo; argument to &ldquo;cd&rdquo; takes you back one directory.<br/>
And finally, for today, is the &ldquo;mkdir&rdquo; command. This is responsible for creating a new directory. This is just like creating a new folder by right-clicking on the finder window and selecting the &ldquo;Create a new folder&rdquo; option. Let&rsquo;s just create a directory called &ldquo;favs&rdquo; for purposed of demonstration. You can do this by typing:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>mkdir favs
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
You can use this folder to put all your favorite stuff in. If that&rsquo;s what you want to do. As you can see the &ldquo;mkdir&rdquo; command took 1 argument that specifies the name of the new directory that you want to create and in this situation we created a new directory named &ldquo;favs&rdquo;. We verify that by using the &ldquo;ls&rdquo; command and seeing the output of that contains &ldquo;favs&rdquo;. If you want you can even go inside your newly created directory by typing:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>cd favs</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
However it shouldn&rsquo;t be too surprising that a new directory won&rsquo;t have anything inside of it yet. You can once again verify that by typing:
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>ls</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
Which shows all files and folders in that directory (this time nothing will show up).</p>

<p>Get ready for the next post where I show you how to delete files and folders, create new files, and show what&rsquo;s inside of a file. All by using a terminal Thanks for reading. Hope to see you on here soon!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
